John Wieners Papers 1986.0010
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
John Wieners Papers
1958-1986
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1986.0010
0.75 Linear Feet
Born in 1934, near Boston, John Wieners studied at Black Mountain College from 1955-1956. An associate of the San Francisco and Beat Writers, he is an American poet and gay activist.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was purchased by the University of Connecticut from various individuals from 1976 through 1986.
Biography
Born in Boston, Massachusetts, on 6 January 1934, John Wieners is the son of Albert Eugene and Anna Elizabeth (Laffan) Wieners. He studied at Boston College (A.B., 1954) and attended Black Mountain College (1955-1956) and SUNY-Buffalo (1965-1969). Wieners was an actor and stage manager for the Poets Theatre in Boston, MA, in 1956 before establishing and editing the magazine, Measure (1957-1962). He has been a teacher at the Beacon Hill Free School in Boston since 1973. The author of over 25 books and three plays, Wieners has won awards from the Poets Foundation (1962), New Hope Foundations (1963), National Institute of Arts and Letters (1968) and a grant from the National Endowment for the Arts (1968-1969). A member of the Academy of American Poets, Wieners resides in Boston, MA>.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of correspondence and a small amount of manuscripts. The bulk of the materials are those assembled by Raymond Foye in the course of editing Wieners' Selected Poems, 1958-1984 (Santa Barbara: Black Sparrow Press, 1986). These files include correspondence with Wieners and others (1984-1985) and Allen Ginsberg>'s working manuscripts for the book's foreword.
Twentieth century.; Manuscripts (document genre); Correspondence; Poets; Kyger, Joanne; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997; Rumaker, Michael, 1932-; Foye, Raymond, 1957-; Meltzer, David; McNaughton, Duncan, 1942-; Di Prima, Diane; MacAdams, Lewis, 1944-; Creeley, Robert, 1926-2005; Dorn, Edward; Berkson, Bill; Fagin, Larry
- Series I: Manuscripts, 1958-197?
  - "Ailsa's Last Will and Testament", 197? (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Behind the State Capitol: or Cincinnati Pike, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ephemera, 1965-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "I have Swallowed my teeth...", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Justice", 197? (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Klugwerth", 197? (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Memories of You, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Selected Poems—foreword (Ginsberg), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "To Ross", 197? (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Unidentified mss, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1967-1986
  - Minkhoff, George, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Wieners, John, 195?-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12-18)
  - Selected Poems, 1958-1984
    - Alexander, Robert, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Allen, Donald, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Angulo, Gui de, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Barnett, Anthony, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Berkson, Bill, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bertholf, Robert, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bockris, Victor, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Butterick, George, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Byrne, Marie, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Ceely, John, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Cooper, Dennis, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Corbett, Bill, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Creeley, Robert, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Crozier, Andrew, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Cullen, Rosemary L., 1984 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Curtiss, Julie, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Davidson, Michael, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - DeLoach, Allen, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Di Prima, Diane, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Dorn, Edward, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Doyle, Kirby, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Ellingham, Lewis, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Elmslie, Kenward, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Eshleman, Clayton, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Fagin, Larry, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Foye, Raymond, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Friedman, Michael, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Friedman, Richard, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Gatlin, Debbie, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Ginsberg, Allen, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Glover, Albert, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Goldberg, Jeff, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Gosciak, Josh, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Grundel, Bonnie, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Gruttola, Raffael de, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Harwood, Lee, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Irby, Ken, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Jordan, Larry, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Kahn, Paul, 1984? (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Killian, Kevin, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Kyger, Joanne, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Lansing, Gerrit, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Logan, Ruth, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - MacAdams, Lewis, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Martin, John, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Mason, Alexandra, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Matson, Erin, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - McNaughton, Duncan, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Meltzer, David, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Morgan, Bill, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Morrow, Bradford, 1985? (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Patler, Louis, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Perry, Sigrid P., 1984 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Prynne, Jeremy, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Rebec, Estelle, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Rumaker, Michael, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Taylor, Saundra, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Tebor, Dawn, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Timby, Sara, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Volkersz, Evert, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Wieners, John, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Wildley, Lynne, 1984? (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Wilkinson, John, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 81)